Guide to the University of Chicago Student and Alumni Papers and Ephemera Collection circa 1901-2012
University of Chicago Library
University of Chicago. Student and Alumni Papers and Ephemera. Collection
circa 1901-2019
10 linear feet (14 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Student and Alumni Papers and Ephemera Collection consists of correspondence, class notes, football ticket books, dance cards, freshman orientation programs, diplomas, convocations programs, invitations, brochures from various convocation activities, and other materials related to student life at the University of Chicago. The collection also includes alumni reminiscences and class reunion materials.
Information on Use
Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope Note
The Student and Alumni Papers and Ephemera Collection consists of correspondence, class notes, football ticket books, dance cards, freshman orientation programs, diplomas, convocations programs, invitations, brochures from various convocation activities, and other materials related to student life at the University of Chicago. The collection also includes alumni reminiscences and class reunion materials.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Subject Headings
Elliott, Josephine Mirabella; Fuzy, Alice G.; Johnstone, Alice; Scott, Catherine Sample; Wells, Elisabeth Boykin; Ziobrowski, Frank G.; University of Chicago; Students; Student life
INVENTORY
- Josephine Mirabella Elliott (Ph.B in Romance languages, 1932):, Annual student ticket book for football game, 1929 Annual student ticket book for football game, 1930 Certificate of Admission, University of Chicago, June 1928 Freshman Orientation Week paraphernalia, 1928 Freshman Orientation Week program, 1929 Football program, annotated, 1930 Membership card, Y.W.C.A. Dance card, Phi Delta Upsilon formal, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Leonard to Maud (Mrs. W.C.)Chadwick, June 25, 1918 Leonard to Maud (Mrs. W.C.)Chadwick, n.d. Mary "Maurie" Smith to Mirriam, c. 1901 Mary "Maurie" Smith to Mirriam, c. 1903-1904 Mary "Maurie" Smith to Mirriam, c. 1903 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Class notes from a member of the College class of 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Class notes from a member of the College class of 1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Tickets, Wisconsin-Chicago Football game, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Elisabeth Boykin Wells, class of 1924 reminiscences (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous ephemera, Button, "University of Chicago: Unfair to Small Black Business", n.d. Chicago emblem, college tobacco leather, 1908 Chicago emblem, clothes tag (?), n.d. Medal, Intramural University of Chicago, 440 Yard Run Outdoor, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Alice Johnstone, diaries, Hibernian Bank date book 1910-1911 (most entries appear to be from 1918) Handbook of the University of Chicago, 1915-1916 Handbook of the University of Chicago, 1916-1917 Handbook of the University of Chicago, 1917-1918 Handbook of the University of Chicago, 1918-1919 Handbook of the University of Chicago, 1919-1920 Student Handbook of the University of Chicago, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Catherine Sample Scott, cards, photograph, postcards, copy of Press Impressions, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Catherine Sample Scott, minutes for Dramatic Association, programs from University of Chicago performances, clippings, correspondence regarding a position as college aide, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Catherine Sample Scott, convocation material including programs, invitations, diplomas relating to graduation and induction into Phi Beta Kappa Society (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Alice G. Fuzy, memorabilia, Admissions certificate: letter, certificate, and envelope confirming admittance to the University, July 1931 Invitations to convocation reception (four copies), June 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Alice G. Fuzy, memorabilia, Convocation ephemera: receipts and notices from Registrar's and Bursar's Office for graduation, two tickets to convocation, May-June 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Alice G. Fuzy, memorabilia, Convocation programs (three copies), June 11, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Alice G. Fuzy, memorabilia, Convocation prayer service programs (two + copies), June 9, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Alice G. Fuzy, memorabilia, Diplomas: certificate for completion of exams (September 28, 1933), B.A. (June 11, 1935) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Alice G. Fuzy, memorabilia, Cards, clipping: cards of congratulation, clipping announcing graduation, June 1935 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Anatomy 301-302: outline for Anatomy 301-302: Dissection of Extremities, n.d. Anesthesia: lab notebook, spring 1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Anesthesia: course outline, winter 1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Bacteriology 202: course outlines and notes, spring 1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Bio-Chemistry: laboratory notes, spring 1936 (from Brown University?) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Biochemistry: class notes, fall 1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Class notes, 1938-1940: Surgery, Medicine, Pediatrics) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Defense Mechanisms: class notes, spring 1938 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Neuropathology: class notes, etc., winter 1940 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Obstetrics and Gynecology: course outline, spring 1938 Opthalmology 311: course outline and paper, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Parasitology: class notes, winter 1937 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Pathology: class notes, fall-winter, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Pathology: class notes, winter, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Pathology?, lab notebook?, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Pharmacology 301: class outline, spring 1938 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Laboratory Outline: Pharmacology, n.d. Pharmacology: Syllabus of Prescription Writing by Gerald Fostvedt, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Physiology: class notes, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, class notes and outlines, Public Health: class notes, winter 1938 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, exams, labs, and papers, Exams, 1934-1940 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, exams, labs, and papers, Experiment 212: Secretion of Urine, November 26, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski, exams, labs, and papers, Ziobrowski, Frank, "The Human Arch—Functions—Functional Disorders," n.d. Ziobrowski, Frank, "Traumatic Shock," Physiology 251, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Hematology and Allergy, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Clinical Pathology, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes --Diabetes and Endocrines, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- X-Ray, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Heart, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Psychiatry, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Gastro-Intestinal, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Reno-Vascular, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Obstetrics, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Prescriptions, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Surgical Pathology, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Urology, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Orthopedics, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Eye, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- E. N. T., 1940 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Dermatology, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Neurology, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes -- Infections, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Scrapbook of Virginia Butts, 1940-1942 (Box 5)
- Commencement Program, 1944 (Box 5)
- Frank G. Ziobrowski Notes --Pediatrics, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Notecards, Anon., undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Notecards, Anon., undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Notecards, Anon., undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Notecards, Anon., undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Theodore Hurst, "Reading French: A Contextual Method" (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Theodore Hurst, German Exercises (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Theodore Hurst, An Introduction to Linguistics (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Undergraduate Course Books (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Ruth Bribach -- Elementary German (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Ruth Bribach -- Introduction to the Science of Language (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Ruth Bribach -- The Bibliography... (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Ruth Bribach -- Foundation Principles of the Study of Literature (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Ruth Bribach -- Foundation Principles of the Study of Literature (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Ruth Bribach -- The Canterbury Tales (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Ruth Bribach -- Beginning Old English (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Ruth Bribach -- "The Elements of Old English" (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Ruth Bribach -- Progressive Glee and Chorus Book (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Holze, Anna -- University of Chicago Songbook, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Holze, Anna -- Photographs of Football Games, Stagg Field, 1913-1914 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Cohen, Rabbi Hymen Ezra -- Diaries, 1925-1930 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Class of 1955 -- Chicago Maroon, June 3, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Class of 1962 -- Greeting Cards, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Class of 1963 -- 45th Reunion Memory Book, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Class of 1966 -- SDS Poster, Sit-In Summary, 1966, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Class of 1967 -- Memory Books, Songbook, Panel Discussion Appendices, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Class of 1968, "Living at War," 1968 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Class of 1968 -- Panel Discussion Appendices, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Class of 1971 -- 35th Reunion Class Book, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Class of 1972 -- 35th Reunion Memory Book, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Class of 1973 -- 35th Reunion Memory Book, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Class of 1978 -- 30th Reunion Memory Book, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Radford, Neil A., "Filming the Library Catalog During the Troubles of 1969," circa 2010 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Bacher, Anne Harris, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Bayles, Ann, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Bell, Jordy, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Beltt, Bruce, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Brill, Joan Reisman, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Brossard, Carlos, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Cook, Sally, New University Thought, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Cook, Sally, New University Thought, email, 1963-2008 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Cook, Sally, Chicago Maroons, Clippings, Policy Statement, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Cook, Sally, the Hyde Park-Kenwood Urban Renewal Years.. ., 1965 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Dann, Meryl, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Feiveson, Al, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Glazer, Gerald, email, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Johnston, Neal, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Keenan, Claudia, email, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Kelly, Michael G., email, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Kinkley, Jeff, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Lehrer, Fred, email, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: McReynolds, R. Michael, email, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Michaelson, Robert: Correspondence, Flyer, "Faculty Voice," 1962-2008 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Moldaver, Lee, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Morris, David, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Ostrow, David, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Phillips, William L., email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Poster, John, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Reid, David, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Rogers, Wallett, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Speed, John, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Strausberg, Claire Kuhn, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Classes of 1960-1972 Reminiscences: Vernoff, Charles, email, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Panel Discussion: "Remembering the '60s," CD Recording, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- NCAA Ribbons, 1929-1930 (Box 9, Folder 38)
- Kaufman, Arthur -- Letters and Clippings (Annotated Photocopies), 1963-1966 (Box 9, Folder 39)
- McReynolds, R. Michael -- UC Congress of Racial Equality, Reply to Report, Poster, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 40)
- Commencement Program, Photographs, 1904 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Student Reminiscences, emails, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Johnson, Elizabeth: University of Chicago in Color (Souvenir Scrapbook), undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
- "We Are Chicago," Exhibition Memory Cards [1 of 2], 2012 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- "We Are Chicago," Exhibition Memory Cards [2 of 2], 2012 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Class of 1907 Memorabilia: University Address Books (C. F. Axelson), 1904, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Class of 1907 Memorabilia: Tenth Through 45th Reunion Mailings, 1917-1952 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Class of 1907 Memorabilia: University of Chicago Magazine, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Class of 1907 Memorabilia: Fiftieth and Sixtieth Reunion Mailings and Tower Topics, 1957, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Class of 1907 Memorabilia: Harold Higgins Swift Memorial Service (Typescript of Program?), 1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- University of Chicago Songbook, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Gartman, Charles: Kappa Sigma Fraternity Shield, circa 1920 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Souvenir Album, The University of Chicago, 1908 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Portrait, India Pearle Hamilton Molloy, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
- S.D.S. and other Political Buttons, Fabric Scarf, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Class of 1965: Chicago Tribune Sunday Magazine, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Cooke, Sally: Clipping, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Class of 1963: Joan Baez in Concert, Vinyl Record, Notes, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Magazine Clippings, Offprints, 1964-1968 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Rockefeller Chapel Choir Programs, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Student Political Fliers, S.D.S. New Left Notes, circa 1967 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Theater and Concert Programs (Non-University of Chicago), 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Theater Programs, Playbills (Non-University of Chicago), 1967-1969, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Theater Programs, University of Chicago, 1968, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): University of Chicago Commencement Program, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Chicago Sun-Times Supplement (Martin Luther King, Jr.), 1968 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): "Dumb Show" Booklet, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Maroon, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): The New Militant, New Left Notes, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Young Socialist Magazine, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Barney Keirnan's Pub Literary Magazine, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Peirce, Anita L. (Pine): Seed Newspaper, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Fortune Magazine Reprint, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Alumni Foundation Brochures, 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Art Comprehensive Exam, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Blackfriars Program, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- English 102 Exercises [1 of 2], 1935-1936 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- English 102 Exercises [2 of 2], 1936 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- English Qualifying and Comprehensive Exams, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- French Tests and Worksheets, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- General Introductory Course in Biology -- Course Materials, 1933-1937 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Geographic Exploration Outline, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- German Course Materials, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Home Ec. Department Newsletter, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Humanities Introductory Course Exam, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- "Observation of Young Children," 1935 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Philosophy Comprehensive Exam, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Physical Sciences Comprehensive Exam, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Social Science Quizzes and Course Materials, 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Tags and Button, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- 50th Reunion Materials, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- Tower Topics Map, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Cohn, Alma Katz -- University of Chicago Stationery, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Class of 1968 -- 50th Anniversary Slideshow
- Class of 1969 -- 50th Anniversary Slideshow